# Stephanie Duffieux

WEB DEVELOPER & DESIGNER -



0420 579 085



stephanie.duffieux@gmail.com



Mango Hill, QLD 4509



github.com/Beedeeboom



linkedin.com/in/stephanie-duffieux



twitter.com/Steph\_Duffieux

# Key Skills

- Web Development
- Graphic Design, Web Design
- Customer Service
- Stakeholder engagement
- Administrative and project support.

# **Technical Proficiency**

#### **Tech Stack:**

- HTML, CSS/SASS, Javascript, PHP
- React
- Ruby on Rails
- Twig & Fractal Template Engines
- Boostrap
- PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Git, GitHub, Bitbucket
- VS Code, Brackets
- Wordpress

## **Applications:**

- Adobe CS (Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Adobe XD)
- Microsoft Office Suite

#### **Career Profile:**

Enthusiastic junior web developer and creative graphic designer, making a conscious choice to transition into tech and kick start a career in Software Engineering.

Experience building web applications utilising programming languages such as Ruby, JavaScript, PHP, HTML, CSS, SASS with frameworks such as React, Ruby on Rails and developing web components with PHP template engines Twig and Fractal. 4+ years experience in graphic design, specialising in multimedia marketing, digital and print design. Extensive knowledge of the Adobe Creative Suite (InDesign, Illustrator, Photoshop, Adobe XD) and creating Wordpress websites utilising Elementor and Avada frameworks.

#### **Education:**

#### **Bachelor of Computer Science**

Jul 2020 - Jul 2023

Deakin University, Geelong

#### **Diploma of Information Technology**

Feb 2020 - Aug 2020

Coder Academy, Brisbane

#### **Diploma of Graphic Design**

Jul 2011 - Sep 2012

Martin College of Technology & Design, Brisbane

### **Industry and Personal Skills:**

- Good knowledge of frontend and backend web development (HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, PHP, Ruby on Rails, React).
- Ability to adapt to new programming languages.
- Excellent knowledge in Graphic & Web Design.
- Strong team player and ability to work individually.
- Excellent work ethic and upholding a strict level of confidentiality.
- High level of organisational skills and precise attention to detail.
- Reliable, quick learner, ability to multi task and meet deadlines.

### **Project Links:**

Youneek Mind

(More projects available on Github - github.com/Beedeeboom)

#### **Work Experience:**

#### **Frontend Developer Intern**

Aug 2020 - Sep 2020 | Queensland Urban Utilities

- Assisted the digital department in developing web components for the new design system utilising SASS, HTML, JavaScript and PHP programming languages with Twig and Fractal template engines.
- Designed and developed web components with an "Accessibility first" mindset by implementing coding best practices for user accessibility.
- Developed mobile responsive web components utilising SASS media queries and grid layouts.
- Created new SASS global variables re-usable across the new design system and developed an excellent understanding of how to use existing components and variables to maintain DRY coding principles.
- Participated in daily stand-up meetings and fortnightly SCRUM meetings with the digital team.
- Regularly reported to the Frontend Tech Lead on task progression and developed an excellent understanding of time management, prioritisation of work loads and problem solving skills.

#### **Junior Full Stack Developer**

Feb 2020 - Aug 2020 | Coder Academy, Brisbane

- Programmed computer terminal applications utilising the Ruby programming language and DRY coding principles.
- Created and designed web pages utilising semantic HTML and CSS.
- Developed a forum and a two sided marketplace application utilising the Ruby on Rails framework and PostgreSQL.
- Designed web application prototypes utilising Adobe XD and Figma.
- Participated in group projects developing Javascript MERN stack applications.
- Deployed web applications utilising GitHub and Heroku.
- · Collaborated in group projects utilising Git source control and applying Agile project management methodology.

#### **Freelance Graphic Designer**

Oct 2019 - Current | Luova Design Solutions, Brisbane

 Designed print and digital solutions for start ups and small businesses such as logo design, brand identity, web design and website development (Wordpress), design of social media banners/posts, brochures, business cards and custom designs to suit client needs.

#### **Executive Assistant / Graphic Designer**

2017 - 2019 | Xplore Resources Pty Ltd, Brisbane

- Developed and maintained Wordpress websites for various clients and business partners.
- Managed all graphic design duties including design of promotional materials for large mining events.
- Designed all print and digital content for large mining tender submissions (300-500 pages) within tight deadlines.
- Created logo and brand identity designs for various clients and business partners.
- Performed high level administration support to assist the CEO (diary management, agenda preparation, minute taking, coordination of executive communications, preparation of presentations).

#### **Customer Account Manager**

2015 - 2017 | APN / News Corp, Yandina Qld

- Ensured timely and accurate completion of all administrative duties including customer account management.
- Communicated with internal and external stakeholders to ensure customer needs were met.
- Coordinated and managed issues and communicated with all key stakeholders.

- Collaborated with sale mangers to contribute in developing and maintaining client relationships.
- Developed dynamic and effective working relationships with external customers, business unit heads, team leaders and team members.

#### Customer Service Officer / Graphic Designer (Bi-Lingual French & English)

2013-2015 | Mail Marketing & Telemarketing Solutions Pty Ltd, Brisbane

- Assisted the arts & production department in designing brochures using the Adobe Creative Suite.
- Provided administrative support to the Customer Service department and assist in daily banking, data entry, mail room duties and proof reading of various translated documents English to French.
- Provided a high level of customer service to international clients (English and French).

#### **Customer Service Officer / Personal Assistant to CEO**

2009-2011 | Pacific Air Cargo Pty Ltd, Brisbane

- Managed all bookkeeping duties, accounts receivables / payables, invoicing.
- Provided personal assistance to the CEO, diary management, coordinate meetings and travel arrangements.
- Handled international air and sea shipments promptly and provide excellent customer service.

#### **References:**

Contact details available on request

#### **Thibaut Allender**

Frontend Tech Lead | Queensland Urban Utilities

#### **Sally Hookey**

Customer Service Manager | APN / News Corp

#### **Theresa Pretenthaler**

Customer Service Manager | MMTS Pty Ltd

#### **Frederic Pierson**

Chief Executive Officer | Pacific Air Cargo Pty Ltd